

My Contact

jboyd115@icloud.com

() 491778805055

Zollernweg 1 Baden-Baden, Germany

www.linkedin.com/in/jared-boyd-89963b266/

https://github.com/boydlakers15/certificates-jared

Valid EU work visa

Achievements

2020 Successfully managed a \$150 million project at Tesla in California to install 40 robotic cell groups, containing over 300 robots, in 21 days.

2015 – Managed multiple projects worth over 2021 \$500 million.

2011 – Involved with the production of millions of 2021 cars around the world

Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- React
- React
- GitSQL
- C#
- Communication skills
- Teamwork and collaboration
- Leadership and management
- Problem-solving
- Creativity and innovation
- and HMI via TIA Portal

 Language Skills

• Siemens S7-1200 PLC

• Java / JavaScript

English- Native proficiency

• German - Beginner

References

- Scott Broome/Premeire Automation
 - Owner
 - +1 (205) 514-3540
- Clyde Mitchell/ IWG
 - o Owner
 - +1 (863) 344-0644

Jared Boyd

About Me

With over a decade of experience managing automation system installations, including leading teams in robotics, software, mechanical, and electrical departments, I am now eager to transition into software engineering/DevOps space and build upon the technical skill set obtained from the successful completion of a Web Development bootcamp.

Education Background

WBS Coding School

Feb 2023 - June 2023

 Studied: Javascript, HTML React v6, CSS, SQL, Git, Bootstrap, Scrum, Express

Hillcrest High School

Aug 2001 - June 2004

Professional Experience

Heckert Engineering GmbH | Servicemitarbeiter

April 2021- March 2022 | Porsche & Mercedes; Stuttgart, Germany

 Mechanical installation of a production System for Paint Shop.

Premiere Automation | Mechanical & Electrical Coordinator, Mechanical Supervisor

February 2019 - June 2020 | Mercedes; Charleston, SC

- Maintenance support of the Body Shop for the Mercedes Bens Van Line
- Overseeing the handling of production training & maintenance training
- Creation of process documentation for production line components

FFT | Mechanical & Electrical Coordinator, Mechanical Supervisor

August 2017- January 2019 | Mercedes; Charleston, SC, Volkswagen; Chattanooga, TN

- Manager for the Installation of Automated Production Systems
- Open communication with customers on project situations
- o Creation and execution of project schedules

International Workers Group (IWG) | Site Manager : Formally Motion Industiral

January 2015 - July 2017 | Many projects all over the USA

- Mechanical and electrical installation
- o Robot controllers Installation
- o Pulling cable and panel termination
- Cable tray installation
- PLC installation





Software Projects

Windturbine Repair Website:

https://boydlakers15.github.io/Wind-turbine-App-Frontend

https://boydlakers15.github.io/Wind-Turbine-App-Backend

- Bootcamp Final Project
- App was built with Vite React, CSS, Node.js, MongoDB, Express and more.
- Website features include Employee login, Employee online status, live chat, work order creation and order status, pdf file creation of selected work orders
- Client application deployed to https://profounddasik-d1357e.netlify.app
- Render deployed backend

Weather App:

- Weather app implemented using C# and API's
- Application was built in Visual Studio IDE

Jared Boyd

Professional Experience

Motion Industrial | Installation Manager

February 2011 - January 2015 | Many projects all over the USA · On-site

Mechanical and electrical installation

- Robot controllers
- Pallet racking
- o Pulling cable and panel termination
- Cable tray installation
- PLC installation

King Rock Racing | Mechanical lead/Racecar Driver

June 2009 - Jan 2011 | Salt Lake City, UT

- o Team Leader for all mechanics of the Racecar
- Racecar driver for the team

Fire Services Inc. | Mechanical Supervisor

June 2004 - June 2009 | Salt Lake City, UT

o Installation of fire suppression systems

Certifications

- Agile Software Development: Scrum for Developers (2018)
 - o Issued March 2023
 - o Credential ID AbjB2-1in7B32yCQq6tWloyFKwkT
- Build a Website with HTML, CSS, and GitHub Pages Skill Path
 - o Issued Mar 2023
 - o Credential ID 640843676E
- Learn JavaScript Course Codecademy
 - o Issued Mar 2023
 - o Credential ID 6407213A31
- Learn JavaScript: Error Handling Course
 - o Issued Mar 2023
 - o Credential ID 6405B6EC31
- Scrum: The Basics
 - o Issued Mar 2023
 - o Credential ID AQnsYvg6YWJZSocQzjPPn-hKT6i
- Learn Bootstrap Course Codecademy
 - o Issued Feb 2023
 - o Credential ID 63FCB10088
- Learn Git & GitHub Course Codecademy
 - o Issued Feb 2023

- Goethe Deutsch Zertifikat A1, 2020
 - Issued 2020
- Siemens S7-1200 PLC and HMI via TIA Portal 32 hour training course
 - o Issued 2020
- Introduction to Programming: Java, C# 20 hour training course
 - Issued 2020
- Learn React Router v6 Course
 - o Issued Apr 2023
 - o Credential ID 642A8828F1
- Learn SQL Course
 - Issued Apr 2023
 - Credential ID 64350C13C7
- Agile Foundations LinkedIn Online Training Courses
 - Issued Mar 2023
 - Credential ID AarJlleBH01cQ9hUXbn9TwrJ8QrC

